<xml>
<title>Summary</title>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;
Validating techniques for biogeochemistry products can take spatial
and temporal factors into consideration by making use of a
neighbouring method technique. The technique comprises that a window
of variability is applied to the model output results. The variability
window allows comparing satellite pixel values with model pixel values
that are in the neighbourhood of the pixel of concern. The shape of
the window can be rigid or flexible according to what the information
is wanted from the validation. Three shapes for the variability window
were tested in time and space.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The neighbouring method as applied in this work, concentrates on
validating biogeochemistry models with satellite data. The technique
is suitable for validating a biogeochemistry model with point.
Satellite validation has as a consequence only surface chlorophyll
model output is regarded.  Though the principles for the temporal and
spatial dimension are the same, time is usually not tested in
applications of neighbouring method techniques. Hence, we demonstrate
the use of a window variability in time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Below the different variability windows that were tested are described
(more possibilities exits). The window method is visualised by
representing the databases matrices as cubes, as they are 3D (time,
longitude and latitude). The satellite cube is blue, the model output
cube light green and the output used after applying the window is dark
green. See &lt;a href="text/product_quality_stats_biogeochemistry_windows.html"
target="_blank"&gt;the window methods used here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

Three types of skill metrics are used to compare satellite and model
results: details of the &lt;a
href="text/product_quality_stats_biogeochemistry_skill_metrics.html"
target="_blank"&gt;classic continuous skill metrics, categorical
metrics and the p90 value maps can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

To make sure the evaluation of the neighbouring method is not biased
by model or area specific anomalies, three different domains were
tested. The satellite products of MyOcean were used. The details of
&lt;a href="text/product_quality_stats_biogeochemistry_domain.html"
target="_blank"&gt;the domains used are found here&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;

</body>
</xml>

